Guide to the Sisterhood is Global Institute Records, 1963-2010 and undated, bulk 1980-2002 RL.01185
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Conferences and Programs Series, 1980-2005, 17 boxes
  - Other Events Subseries, 1980-2005, bulk 1993-2001
    - 1995
      - Mar., Summit for Social Development, Copenhagen, Denmark
        - Speeches (Box CONF11)
      - Apr., Empowering Women in the Global South, Washington D.C. (Box CONF11)
      - Apr., Women in Muslim Societies, Berlin, Germany
        - Correspondence (Box CONF11)
        - Papers presented (Box CONF11)
      - Sept., UN World Conference, Beijing, China
        - Caritas (Box CONF11)
        - Commentary on the Platform for Action (Box CONF11)
        - Conference materials (Box CONF11)
        - Correspondence (Box CONF11)
    - 1995 (Box CONF12)
      - Sept., UN World Conference, Beijing, China
        - Clippings, speech materials (Box CONF12)
        - Diversity Tent (Box CONF12)
        - Funding (Box CONF12)
        - General documents (Box CONF12)
        - Hotel (Box CONF12)
        - Member questionnaire, 2 folders (Box CONF12)
        - NGO accreditation (Box CONF12)
        - Opposition letters (Box CONF12)
        - Panels (Box CONF12)
        - Platform for Action, 2 folders (Box CONF12)
        - Reception (Box CONF12)
        - Registration information (Box CONF12)
        - SIGI panels (Box CONF12)
        - Travel (Box CONF12)
        - Various preparatory meetings (Box CONF12)
    - 1995 (Box CONF13)
      - Sept., UN World Conference, Beijing, China
        - Women's Environment and Development Organization (WEDO) (Box CONF13)
        - A Woman's Creed, translations, 2 folders (Box CONF13)
        - Women Stand on the Road to Beijing program (Box CONF13)
    - 1996
      - June, United Nations Conference on Human Settlements (Habitat II), Istanbul, Turkey, 2 folders (Box CONF13)
      - Sept., Association for Women's Rights in Development (AWID) Seventh International Forum, Washington D.C. (Box CONF13)
      - Sept., America's Commitment, Md. (Box CONF13)
      - Sept., Fundamentalism and Women's Human Rights, Palo Alto, Calif. (Box CONF13)
      - Oct., State of the World Forum, Calif.
        - Correspondence, press release (Box CONF13)
        - General conference materials (Box CONF13)
      - Nov., Middle East Studies Association (MESA) conference, Providence, R.I. (Box CONF13)
    - 1997
      - Jan., Florida Atlantic University lecture by Mahnaz Afkhami (Box CONF13)
      - Feb.-Mar., Woman's National Democratic Club, Washington D.C. (Box CONF13)
      - Mar., Center for the Global South, Washington D.C. (Box CONF13)
      - Mar., Islam and Justice panel, Washington D.C. (Box CONF13)
      - Mar., Prospects of Women's Rights in Afghanistan, Washington D.C. (Box CONF13)
      - Mar., Women Writers from the Mediterranean, Tel Aviv, Israel (Box CONF13)
      - Apr., Columbia University discussion with Mahnaz Afkhami (Box CONF13)
      - Apr., CSW meeting (Box CONF13)
      - Apr., LaSalle conference on Islam and the West, Philadelphia, Pa. (Box CONF13)
      - Apr., Worldnet dialogue, Social, Political, Economic Status of Women, Washington D.C. (Box CONF13)
      - May, First International Women's Leadership Conference, Boston, Mass. (Box CONF13)
      - June, National Women's Studies Association Annual Conference, St. Louis, Mo. (Box CONF13)
      - June, Passages, Madrid, Spain (Box CONF13)
      - July, UNESCO Adult Education Conference, Hamburg, Germany (Box CONF13)
      - Oct., Middle East Institute discussion (Box CONF13)
      - Nov., Towards a More Compassionate Society in the 21st Century: State of the World Forum, Stanford University
        - Active program, contact list (Box CONF13)
        - Correspondence (Box CONF13)
        - Possible speakers (Box CONF13)
    - 1997 (Box CONF14)
      - Nov., Towards a More Compassionate Society in the 21st Century: State of the World Forum, Stanford University
        - Cannot attend
          - Fry, Hedy (Box CONF14)
          - Haq, Khadija (Box CONF14)
          - Maathai, Wangari (Box CONF14)
          - Tyson, Laura (Box CONF14)
    - 1998
      - June, Vienna Plus Five, Ottawa, Canada (Box CONF14)
      - June, Women's Global Leadership Institute, Rutgers, N.J. (Box CONF14)
      - Sept., World Bank, Washington D.C. (Box CONF14)
      - Oct., Canadian Council of Muslim Women, Ontario, Canada (Box CONF14)
      - Oct., Friedrich Ebert Foundation Retreat, N.Y. (Box CONF14)
      - Oct., McArthur Foundation discussion, Chicago, Ill. (Box CONF14)
      - Oct., Strong Women Keep Coming, Washington D.C. (Box CONF14)
      - Nov., A Woman's Place premiere (Box CONF14)
      - Nov., Middle East Institute, Washington D.C. (Box CONF14)
      - Nov., The Women's Foreign Policy Group, Washington D.C. (Box CONF14)
      - Dec., MESA session (Box CONF14)
      - Dec., Redefining Feminism: Voices from the Middle East, Washington D.C. (Box CONF14)
      - No month, Conferences (Box CONF14)
    - 1999
      - Jan., 50th Anniversary of The Second Sex, France (Box CONF14)
      - Feb., Women's legislation meeting (Box CONF14)
      - Feb., NED, India (Box CONF14)
      - Feb., Women Make Movies: Divorce Iranian Style, New York City (Box CONF14)
      - Mar., Carnegie Workshop on Civil Society, Warrenton, Va. (Box CONF14)
      - Mar., Mount Saint Mary's College (Box CONF14)
      - Mar., Phoenix International Women's Day, Phoenix, Ariz. (Box CONF14)
      - Apr., Amnesty International Annual Meeting, Minneapolis, Minn. (Box CONF14)
      - Apr., Off-the-Record lecture series, New York City (Box CONF14)
      - Apr., World Bank (Box CONF14)
      - June, Beijing + 5 preparations (Box CONF14)
      - June, World Commission on Water Conference, Washington D.C.
        - General materials (Box CONF14)
        - Wyndham Bristol hotel (Box CONF14)
      - Aug., Journey of Hope conference, Boston, Mass. (Box CONF14)
      - Oct., A Map of Hope, New York (Box CONF14)
      - Oct., Mill's College: Women's Leadership Institute (Box CONF14)
      - Oct., Women's Human Rights Resources Strategy Workshop, Toronto, Canada (Box CONF14)
      - Oct., World Movement for Democracy Meeting, Lisbon, Portugal (Box CONF14)
      - Nov., Atwater Library events, Montreal, Canada (Box CONF14)
      - Nov., AWID Forum, Washington D.C.
        - Biographies, general information (Box CONF14)
    - 1999 (Box CONF15)
      - Nov., AWID Forum, Washington D.C.
        - Correspondence
          - General (Box CONF15)
          - Rao, Aruna (Box CONF15)
        - Exhibit (Box CONF15)
        - Final plenary (Box CONF15)
        - Mentor/Youth Project (Box CONF15)
        - Program
          - General (Box CONF15)
          - Press release (Box CONF15)
      - Nov., MESA: Association for Middle East Women's Studies (AMEWS) session (Box CONF15)
      - Nov., Woodrow Wilson Center Meeting (Box CONF15)
      - Dec., CBC Newsworld (Box CONF15)
      - No month, Announcements, upcoming events, and conference programs, 2 folders (Box CONF15)
    - 2000
      - Mar.-Apr., Feminist Expo 2000, Baltimore, Md. (Box CONF15)
      - Mar.-Oct., World March of Women 2000
        - Materials
          - General (Box CONF15)
          - Information, notes, correspondence, 3 folders (Box CONF15)
    - 2000 (Box CONF16)
      - May-June, UN World Conferences, materials, 2 folders (Box CONF16)
      - June, Beijing + 5, New York
        - Correspondence (Box CONF16)
        - Materials, 5 folders (Box CONF16)
      - No month, Announcements and conference programs (Box CONF16)
    - 2001 (Box CONF17)
      - Aug., World Conference against Racism (WCAR), Durban, South Africa
        - General (Box CONF17)
        - Post-conference materials (Box CONF17)
        - WCAR-NGO declaration and programme of action (Box CONF17)
      - Oct., Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting, Brisbane, Australia (Box CONF17)
      - Oct., From Victimization to Criminalization, Ottawa, Canada (Box CONF17)
      - Oct., Think Tank for Democratic Development in the Middle East and North Africa (Box CONF17)
      - Oct., Youth Employment Summit, Washington D.C. (Box CONF17)
      - Nov., Shifting Sands - Knowledge in Our Changing World, Montreal, Canada (Box CONF17)
      - No month, Announcements and conference programs (Box CONF17)
    - 2002
      - Nov., Small Arms After the UN Conference: The Way Forward, Ottawa, Canada (Box CONF17)
      - Aug.-Sept., World Summit on Sustainable Development, Johannesburg, South Africa (Box CONF17)
      - Oct., World Population Awareness Week (Box CONF17)
    - 2005
      - No month, UN World Conference on Women, Finland (Box CONF17)
- Photographic Materials Series, 1989-2002 and undated, 2 boxes
  A collection of photographs from conferences attended or organized by SIGI members, official meetings and visitis, as well as some unidentified prints. Photograph from SIGI's workshops are also available. The series contains standard, panoramic, and contact prints, and some developed film. Organized in alphabetical order, by name of event.
  - Afifa Dirani Arsanias, Lebanon, 1995 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Albright meeting, 1996 May 8 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Algerian journalist at SIGI, 1997 (Box PHOTO1)
  - AWID (Association for Women's Rights in Development, 1996 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Beijing (Faith and Freedom Celebration), 1995 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Beijing (includes Durga Sob gives interview), 1995 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Beijing and Beyond conference, 1996 May 11-12 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Central Asian activists' visit, 1995 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Claiming Rights Middle East Institute, 1998 Feb. (Box PHOTO1)
  - General Meeting, 1999 June (Box PHOTO1)
  - Jordan, 1999 May (Box PHOTO1)
  - La Salle University, 1997 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Lebanon, 1998 May-June (Box PHOTO1)
  - Marfua, Uzbekistan, 1998 May and undated (Box PHOTO1)
  - Papandreau, M., 1993, 1994 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Philippines, 1989 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Princess Sarwath, 1994 Nov. (Box PHOTO1)
  - Religion, Culture, and Human Rights conference, 1994 Sept. 9-10, 2 folders (Box PHOTO1)
  - Rites of Passage (conference on women's human rights education), 1997 Sept. 26-27 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Sheherezad event, 1999 Apr. (Box PHOTO1)
  - SIGI
    - Annual General Meeting, Ms. Magazine headquarters, New York City, 2000 (Box PHOTO1)
    - Gala, Robin Morgan's garden, New York City, 2000 (Box PHOTO1)
    - Montreal offices, events, 2000-2002 (Box PHOTO1)
    - News, 1999 Spring-Summer (Box PHOTO1)
    - Programs in Peshawan, Azerbaijan, 1999-2000 (Box PHOTO1)
    - Training Meeting, Washington D.C., 1998 (Box PHOTO1)
    - Workshop in Jordan, Amman, 1999 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Steering Committee meetings, 1993-1995 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Training after Rights of Passage conference, 1998 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Unidentified photographs, 1993 and undated (Box PHOTO1)
  - Various members, undated (Box PHOTO1)
  - Vienna, 1993 (Box PHOTO1)
  - Violence Expert Group meeting, 1998 Oct. (Box PHOTO2)
  - Visitors to SIGI, 1997 (Box PHOTO2)
  - Women from Uzbekistan in SIGI office, 1997 July (Box PHOTO2)
  - Workshop on violence, Syria, 1998 (Box PHOTO2)
  - Years 1994-1996, 1994-1996 (Box PHOTO2)
- Subject Files Series, 1980-2001 and undated, 15 boxes
  Includes a wide spectrum of materials collected and organized by SIGI staff: newspaper clippings, alerts and newsletters, ephemeral publications, country reports, occasional correspondence, as well as individual articles and working papers. There are also interview transcripts collected as part of the Women's Global Film Project. The largest categories comprise materials on reproductive rights, immigrant and refugee women, women’s rights, violence against women, and women in development. Smaller groups of folders cover motherhood, the economic and political status of women, and the precarious situation of women in armed conflicts. A substantial number of the working papers in the series have been published by the Women in Development Division of the World Bank. Organized alphabetically by subject or author's name.
  - Abortion and reproductive rights (Box SUBJ1)
    - News journals and reports, 1994-2000, 5 folders (Box SUBJ1)
    - Reports and articles, 2000-2001, 2 folders (Box SUBJ1)
  - Abortion, genetic and reproductive rights
    - Articles, general information, 1985-1989 (Box SUBJ1)
  - Advertising
    - Articles, 1987-1992 (Box SUBJ1)
  - Aging
    - Income security, 1988-1989 (Box SUBJ1)
  - Aging (Box SUBJ2)
    - Superannuation Conference in New Zealand, 1989 Mar. (Box SUBJ2)
  - Association for Women in Development, The
    - Correspondence and newsletters, 1998-2001, 2 folders (Box SUBJ2)
  - Children's rights
    - Booklets, pamphlets, and reports, 1991-2000, 2 folders (Box SUBJ2)
  - Civil Society/Democratization
    - Newsletters, 1994-1998 (Box SUBJ2)
  - Economic equality
    - Newsletters, pamphlets, and reports, 1997-2000, 2 folders (Box SUBJ2)
  - Education
    - Articles and newsletters, 1989-1991 (Box SUBJ2)
    - Reports and working papers, 1989-1998, Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box SUBJ2)
  - Education (Box SUBJ3)
    - Reports and working papers, 1989-1998, Folder 3 of 3 (Box SUBJ3)
  - Female genital mutilation
    - Bulletins, correspondence and reports, 1982-2001, 5 folders (Box SUBJ3)
    - Toubia, Nahid, review process, 1992-1993 (Box SUBJ3)
  - Feminism
    - Offen, Karen, Defining Feminism: A Comparative Historical Approach, 1988 (Box SUBJ3)
    - Kirschenbaum, Jill, The Feminization of Management, 1991 (Box SUBJ3)
    - Organizations, bulk materials, 1999-2000, 2 folders (Box SUBJ3)
  - Fertility and family planning (Box SUBJ4)
    - Articles and reports, 1982-1992 (Box SUBJ4)
  - Food and hunger
    - Articles and newsletters, 1985-1991 (Box SUBJ4)
  - Gender equality
    - Booklets, 1985-1995 (Box SUBJ4)
  - Global women's movement
    - Newsletters, 1985-1990 (Box SUBJ4)
  - Globalization
    - Information about FTAA/ZLEA, Quebec, 2001 (Box SUBJ4)
  - HIV/AIDS
    - And Women
      - Articles, 1986-1988, 2 folders (Box SUBJ4)
    - General information, reports, 2001 (Box SUBJ4)
  - Housing
    - Human settlement
      - Reports, 1985-1989 (Box SUBJ4)
    - World's women data sheets, 1980 (Box SUBJ4)
  - Human rights, women's rights
    - Articles and correspondence, 1989, 2 folders (Box SUBJ4)
    - Articles and report, 1989-1990 (Box SUBJ4)
    - Articles and report, 1996-2000 and undated (Box SUBJ4)
    - Beyer, Lisa, Life Behind the Veil, 1990 (Box SUBJ4)
    - Correspondence and report, 1990-1992 (Box SUBJ4)
  - Human rights, women's rights (Box SUBJ5)
    - Education
      - Reports, guides and handbooks, 1993-2001 (Box SUBJ5)
    - Goodman, Ellen, Women Activists in a Hundred Countries, undated (Box SUBJ5)
  - Immigrants and Refugee Women
    - Guides and newsletter, 1995-1999, 2 folders (Box SUBJ5)
    - Newsletters and reports, 1994-2000, 2 folders (Box SUBJ5)
  - International criminal court
    - Alerts, 2002-2003 (Box SUBJ5)
    - Articles and general information, 1997-2001, 3 folders (Box SUBJ5)
  - Legislation
    - Articles and reports, 1989-1992 (Box SUBJ5)
  - Legislation (Box SUBJ6)
    - And Equality
      - Articles and reports, 1999-2001 (Box SUBJ6)
    - In Canada
      - Articles, 2001 (Box SUBJ6)
  - Population and population growth
    - Newsletters and reports, 1988-2001, 2 folders (Box SUBJ6)
  - Pornography
    - Articles and papers, 1989-1992 (Box SUBJ6)
  - Poverty
    - Discussion papers and reports, 1989-2001, 2 folders (Box SUBJ6)
  - Refugees
    - Publications and reports, 1985-1990, 2 folders (Box SUBJ6)
  - Reproductive technologies
    - Articles and papers, 1985-1991 (Box SUBJ6)
  - Sexuality
    - Lesbian and gay human rights
      - Articles and newsletters, 1989-1992 (Box SUBJ6)
      - Articles and reports, 2000-2001 (Box SUBJ6)
  - Statistics on women
    - General, 1999-2001 (Box SUBJ6)
  - Structural adjustment, sustainable development
    - Articles, 1988-2001 (Box SUBJ6)
  - Violence against women (Box SUBJ7)
    - Domestic violence
      - Articles, newsletters and reports, 1990s, 2000, 4 folders (Box SUBJ7)
    - General
      - Articles and papers, 1983-2001, 4 folders (Box SUBJ7)
      - Reports, 1981-1998, Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box SUBJ7)
  - Violence against women (Box SUBJ8)
    - General
      - Reports, 1981-1998, Folder 3 of 3 (Box SUBJ8)
    - In Muslim societies
      - Articles, newsletters and reports, 1989-2001, 2 folders (Box SUBJ8)
    - Prostitution and trafficking
      - Articles, newsletters and reports, 1985-1992, 2 folders (Box SUBJ8)
      - Correspondence, general information and newsletters, 1992-1999, 3 folders (Box SUBJ8)
  - Violence against women (Box SUBJ9)
    - Prostitution and trafficking
      - Reports, 1993-1998, 2 folders (Box SUBJ9)
    - Rape
      - Articles, correspondence, and reports, 1991-2001, 2 folders (Box SUBJ9)
    - Sexual assault and the police
      - Medical guides, studies and reports, 1996-1998, 2 folders (Box SUBJ9)
    - Sexual harassment
      - Articles and reports, 1991-2001 (Box SUBJ9)
  - Women and armed conflict
    - General information, articles, newsletters, and reports, 1991-2000 (Box SUBJ9)
    - Gulf War, articles, 1991 (Box SUBJ9)
  - Women and armed conflict (Box SUBJ10)
    - War crimes, alerts, 1996-2001 (Box SUBJ10)
    - War/terrorism, articles, 1989-1990, 1992 (Box SUBJ10)
    - Women terrorists, 1989 July (Box SUBJ10)
  - Women and development, NGOs and women's groups, 1995-2000, 2 folders (Box SUBJ10)
  - Women and the environment, article, newsletters, reports, 1990s, 2 folders (Box SUBJ10)
  - Women and family
    - Family planning
      - Burton, Sandra, Condolences, It's a Girl, 1990 (Box SUBJ10)
      - Schultz, T. Paul, The Relationship between Local Family Planning Expenditures and Fertility in Thailand, 1976-1981, 1989 Apr. 10 (Box SUBJ10)
    - General information
      - Elmer-Dewitt, Philip, The Great Experiment, 1990 (Box SUBJ10)
      - Toufexis, Anastasia, Coming from a Different Place, 1990 (Box SUBJ10)
    - Marriage, article, 1980s (Box SUBJ10)
    - Motherhood
      - Collier, Paul and Matthew Lockwood, Maternal Education, 1988 Dec. (Box SUBJ10)
      - Maine, Deborah, Prevention of Maternal Deaths in Developing Countries, 1986 Nov. (Box SUBJ10)
      - Safe Motherhood Conference, interview with Barbara Herz, 1987 Feb. (Box SUBJ10)
      - Smolowe, Jill, Last Call for Motherhood, 1990 (Box SUBJ10)
      - Starrs, Ann, Preventing the Tragedy of Maternal Deaths, 1987 Feb. (Box SUBJ10)
      - World Health Organization (WHO)
        - Essential Obstetric Functions, 1986 June (Box SUBJ10)
  - Women and family (Box SUBJ11)
    - Motherhood
      - World Health Organization (WHO)
        - Maternal Mortality Rates, 1986 (Box SUBJ11)
        - Prevention of Maternal Mortality, 1985 Nov. (Box SUBJ11)
      - Winikoff, Beverly, Medical Services to Save Mothers' Lives, 1986 Dec. 1 (Box SUBJ11)
    - Reproductive rights
      - Hart, Nicky, Procreation: The Substance of Female Oppression, 1991 (Box SUBJ11)
      - Reply, undated (Box SUBJ11)
  - Women and the fine arts
    - Gomez, Edward, Quarreling over Quality, 1990 (Box SUBJ11)
    - Women in art, Fall 1991 issue, 1991 (Box SUBJ11)
  - Women in the media, articles, info, 1989, 1991 (Box SUBJ11)
  - Women and peace activism, newsletters, 1999-2001 (Box SUBJ11)
  - Women and religion
    - Baha'i faith
      - Baha'i Studies, 1994 (Box SUBJ11)
      - Baha'is of United States, bulk 1991-1992 (Box SUBJ11)
      - The Baha'is of Iran, bulk 1990-1992 (Box SUBJ11)
      - World Order, 1982-1984, 1988, 2 folders (Box SUBJ11)
    - Christianity, Islam, articles, 1990s (Box SUBJ11)
    - General, conference report, 1996-1997 (Box SUBJ11)
    - Islam
      - Haeri, Shahla, Women, State, and Fundamentalism in Pakistan, 1991 (Box SUBJ11)
      - Keddie, Nikki and Louis Beck, undated (Box SUBJ11)
      - Mernissi, Fatima, Unearthing the Present, 1990 (Box SUBJ11)
      - Wali, Sima, Afghan Women: Strength Amid Adversity, 1990 July 11 (Box SUBJ11)
  - Women and society (Box SUBJ12)
    - Economics
      - Articles and reports, bulk 1980s, 2 folders (Box SUBJ12)
      - Gibbs, Nancy, The Dreams of Youth, 1990 (Box SUBJ12)
      - Latin America, undated (Box SUBJ12)
      - Pietilä, Hilkka, Household and Cultivation, undated (Box SUBJ12)
      - Rudolph, Barbara, Why Can't a Woman Manage More Like a Woman? 1990 (Box SUBJ12)
    - Employment
      - Articles and general info, 1980s, 1990s, 2 folders (Box SUBJ12)
      - International Labour Office, 1985 Mar. (Box SUBJ12)
      - Reports and general info, 1990s, 2 folders (Box SUBJ12)
    - General
      - Amos, Deborah, Lines in the Sand, undated (Box SUBJ12)
      - Borremans, Valentina, Technology and Women's Daily Tasks, 1982 Sept. (Box SUBJ12)
      - Freedman, Jennifer, Women in Iraq, undated (Box SUBJ12)
      - Peters, Emrys L., The Status of Women in Four Middle East Communities, undated (Box SUBJ12)
      - Taylor, Margaret, Papua New Guinea, 1990 (Box SUBJ12)
    - Politics
      - Carlson, Margaret, It's Our Turn, 1990 (Box SUBJ12)
      - Chua-Eoan, Howard G., All in the Family, 1990 (Box SUBJ12)
      - Election guide to women candidates, 1992 (Box SUBJ12)
      - McGeary, Johanna, Challenge in the East, 1990 (Box SUBJ12)
      - On participation, 1990s (Box SUBJ12)
      - Women politicians, 1990s (Box SUBJ12)
  - Women and society (Box SUBJ13)
    - Welfare
      - Articles, 1990, 1992 (Box SUBJ13)
    - Women's suffrage, New Zealand
      - Report, 1993 (Box SUBJ13)
  - Women and technology
    - General
      - Articles, 1984, 1991 (Box SUBJ13)
    - Internet
      - Articles, 2000 Sept. (Box SUBJ13)
  - Women as political prisoners
    - Articles, correspondence, newsletters, 1988-1990, 2 folders (Box SUBJ13)
  - Women in development
    - Agriculture
      - Studies, 1980s (Box SUBJ13)
    - Economics
      - Afsar, Rita and Mahabub Hossain, Credit for Women, 1983 Aug. (Box SUBJ13)
      - Antrobus, Peggy, Women's World: Realities and Choices, 1990 June (Box SUBJ13)
      - Collier, Paul, Women and Structural Adjustment, 1989 Feb. (Box SUBJ13)
      - Duncan, Ann and Masooma Habib, A Review of Selected Economic and Sector Reports,1980-1987, 1988 Nov. (Box SUBJ13)
      - Herz, Barbara, and T. Paul Schultz, Women and Economic Development, 1989 June 1 (Box SUBJ13)
      - Karaosmanoglu, Attila, Enhancing the Role of Asian Women in Development, Oct. 31 (Box SUBJ13)
      - Kenya: The Role of Women in Economic Development, 1989 (Box SUBJ13)
      - Microcredit
        - Newsletters, reports, 1998-2000 (Box SUBJ13)
      - World Bank news release, 1988 Oct. 31 (Box SUBJ13)
      - United Nations, Bank Credit for Rural Women, 1985 Sept. (Box SUBJ13)
    - Education
      - Schultz, T. Paul, Returns to Women's Education, 1989 May (Box SUBJ13)
    - Employment
      - Bolte, Gisela, Don't Blame the Baby, 1990 (Box SUBJ13)
      - Farmers, Merchants and Entrepreneurs, undated (Box SUBJ13)
      - Khandker, Shahidur R., Improving Rural Wages in India, 1989 Aug. (Box SUBJ13)
      - Khandker, Shahidur R.,and Hans Bindswanger, The Effect of Formal Credit, 1989 Aug. (Box SUBJ13)
      - Makihara, Kumiko, Who Needs Equality? 1990 (Box SUBJ13)
      - Molnar, Augusta,and Götz Schreiber, Women and Forestry, 1989 May (Box SUBJ13)
    - General
      - Herz, Barbara, Women in Development, 1987 May 11-12 (Box SUBJ13)
  - Women in development (Box SUBJ14)
    - General
      - Herz, Barbara, Women in Development: Kenya's Experience, 1989 June (Box SUBJ14)
      - Hooper, Emma, Status Review of World Bank Projects Benefiting Women, 1988 Nov. (Box SUBJ14)
      - Qureshi, Moeen, Country Assessments on Women in Development, 1989 (Box SUBJ14)
    - Nutrition
      - Horenstein, Nadine R., Women and Food Security in Kenya, 1989 June (Box SUBJ14)
    - The World Bank
      - Conable, Barber B.
        - Address to the Board of Governors of the World Bank, 1986 Sept. 30 (Box SUBJ14)